Those are Ishbalans, right?
I wonder what
they're doing here.
The military is with them.
I'm sure they're under escort.
This sure is taking a long time.
I heard they're having some
kind of trouble getting water.
What's going on here?
That should delay
their departure a little.
Yeah, that's a relief. Now we don't have to go all the way to the southern camp.
So then, what did you guys do?
You think we did something?
Your pals just suddenly
showed up and grabbed us.
That's awful.
Ishbalans have their
own residential areas.
If you leave them
and band together,
you'll make a good target
for the military.
By the way, Scar said that the Ishbalans had once created a Philosopher's Stone.
We're looking for someone who knows the details about that.
You guys were good friends with Scar-san, right?
We were not good friends
with that guy!
We don't have anything to tell the military.
We do not know anything,
but there is an old man who
lives on the outskirts of Kishua
who might know
something about it.
Chief!
These two should be
able to show you where.
You want us to go there?!
How's that?
At least get the children out of here, is that what you're saying?
Brother, their information
must come at a cost, right?
Equivalent exchange.
It is not part of our teachings,
but I don't see how it can be helped.
Chief...
We'll throw in a shower
at no extra charge.
Get them outside,
or else they'll get cooked!
Let's go!
Sorry...
Hey!
What are you doing?!
Ed! Al!
Hop in!
Winry, did you steal that? You can't do that!
No! They said it's mine if I could fix it.
Who do they think I am?
You guys!
We're out of here!
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Kishua is a bit westward, right?
No problem, no problem!
This sure will help, huh, Brother?
Winry, how long are you
planning to tag along with us?
What's this now,
out of the puny?
That's "out of the blue"!
What I mean is,
go home already.
If I'm not around,
who's going to fix your Automail?
It's hard on me too.
I wanted to return that child homunculus' arm and leg to Brother,
even if it meant
yanking them off of him.
But I couldn't do that
in front of you, Winry.
You couldn't do that
in the first place.
Yeah, Al, you couldn't do that.
But I could, if it was
to achieve our goal.
Brother...
A long time ago,
there was this guy who said it was simple for someone to kill another person.
And indeed, even though it was unavoidable,
I allowed an alchemist named Majhal to die, long ago.
That was an accident.
You were trying to save him, Brother.
And in the 5th Laboratory,
I nearly killed all of those prisoners.
Their lives seemed to pale in comparison with Al's body.
That's what I thought.
But you couldn't do it.
And then there's Scar...
If he stands in my way again,
then, like I did to Greed,
I'm going to...
Kill him?
Are you going to kill that guy?
But that's the man who...
That traitor deserves to be killed.
In any event,
our dangerous battle goes on.
We can't have anyone
slowing us down.
Winry!
We'll see if I slow you down!
It's as though
there was a war here.
You've never even seen a war.
I have.
We have.
This is just like that day...
the day our mom died.
The military people
surrounded the city,
but we didn't
even do anything.
And yet, why did they...
Mom! Mom!
R-Rick!
Mom!
Rick! Stop!
Stop it.
What's the matter?
We don't want to go
to that defiled place.
Okay then, Winry...
Pardon us.
Brother!
Is that...
It's just like the one on Scar-san's right arm.
As well as the one under the 5th Laboratory.
You two, come on out!
Lieutenant! Don't start shooting out of nowhere like that!
I figured you would
be able to dodge it.
If you knew it was us in the
first place, then don't shoot!
That was for
Sergeant Fuery's bruise.
It's all right. We'll wait for Ed and Al here, okay?
Where's the Colonel?
He went back to Central
with Warrant Officer Falman.
So after putting on this sort of display, he ran right back home, huh?
You can't abide the way the Colonel acted against the Ishbalans,
so you attacked the escort train?
No, but right now, it's not as though the Ishbalans are starting any wars,
so you don't have to go around using force to control them.
Don't misunderstand.
There weren't any fatalities
among the Ishbalans this time.
There was one former
soldier who died.
A man named Yoki,
whom you two knew.
Yoki? That old guy is dead?
There were shots fired from the Ishbalan side, and Yoki was hit.
Tensions flared as a result.
The Colonel stepped forward,
and with a display of his power,
he dashed the
Ishbalan's will to fight.
If he hadn't done that, there would have been more casualties on both sides.
Not a bad piece of work
for a soldier.
Are you discriminating against him
because he's a soldier?
You're a member of
the military too, you know.
We've decided to move most of
the people to the camp in the south.
But we have to determine who it was that fired first and punish them.
In order to do that, we're still having several of them remain here.
There's an old man among them, right? The one who lived in that shack.
This is pretty tightly secured here, huh?
Is he a material witness?
No, the old man is not a suspect. We're just protecting him.
Protecting him?
Those are the Ishbalans
who are under arrest, right?
They attacked him. Called him a heretic and an outcast.
Apparently, he's not
regarded as being Ishbalan.
That's ridiculous! I mean, the Ishbalans have always suffered discrimination!
And yet, even among themselves...
Outcasts?
What kind of people are they?
They're defiled.
They're people who have disobeyed the teachings of Ishbala.
He has a tattoo on his face.
That is the mark of an outcast.
When you say they disobey the teachings, what exactly?
It's what Mom told us.
Yeah. Believe in the god Ishbala.
Otherwise, you'll become an outcast.
But I didn't know that
he was an outcast too.
"He"?
The one that you call Scar.
He's an outcast!
He's a traitor!
What kind of person
was your mother?
You know, she was very nice.
Even though her eyes were unwell,
she worked for everyone, in a hospital.
In a hospital?
The Philosopher's Stone, huh?
This is the third time
I've been asked about it.
The third time?
That scarred young man,
and long ago, his older brother asked me the same question.
Scar and his brother?
Then Scar's brother created
a Philosopher's Stone before?
No.
He did not make one.
The young man was too humane.
But why do you know about the Philosopher's Stone?
You're an Ishbalan, right?
I am an outcast.
I learned the Grand Art.
The Grand Art?
Once, we Ishbalans
had a secret art that had been passed down,
which we called the Grand Art.
And with it, we lived
in the lap of luxury.
But then, at some point, the art was sealed away
and became something
forbidden to touch upon.
Those who set their hand to it
were made outcasts
and were unable to
return to their homeland.
The Grand Art allowed one to
alter the form of all things at will.
This act was said to be in
defiance of God's teachings.
Then the Grand Art is alchemy?
Ridiculous! That's not possible!
There's no way that Ishbalans,
who live in the desert and have no
mechanical civilization, could have alchemy.
Is that what you're thinking?
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
When someone's skin and eye color are different,
not thinking that they could be
the same as you are goes both ways.
Would you mind telling us about how to produce a Philosopher's Stone as well?
I doubt that the theory
that you have arrived at
and our own ancient art are all that different.
All that remains is the number of humans sacrificed.
Human... sacrifice?
A city, or a nation...
When they fall, there is resentment and blood
of tens or hundreds of thousands of people, as they die mortified.
When they are taken into
the body of a superior practitioner,
a Philosopher's Stone is produced.
That's just an overblown version of
the way that we know how to make one.
It's not the one
we're hoping to learn.
So, what about Scar-san?
He said he was going to make a Philosopher's Stone.
Why did you teach
my brother about this?!
My brother only wanted to bring the woman he loved back to life.
But in order for that to happen,
the Ishbalan people would have to be destroyed, and their lives offered in sacrifice.
When my brother realized this,
he blamed himself.
He said it was as though
he were the one
who had summoned the disasters that had beset Ishbal!
Here he is!
In here!
You can't!
Not with that many of them!
Is this scene to repeat itself
over and over?
Will the people of Ishbal
ever obtain eternal peace?
If I can obtain a power
beyond theirs...
the Philosopher's Stone...
You would become an outcast?
I already am an outcast.
There are tens of thousands of lives
dwelling within this arm.
An outcast?
A defiled person?
Rick!
"Those who receive pain can still sleep."
"Those who give pain cannot sleep."
In that case, as of today,
I shall not sleep.
Go ahead! Go anyplace else but here, you outcast!
You're sure...
they were named Rockbell?
That's right.
There was a lady doctor
who was scary when she got mad but used to give us candy a lot.
They would treat anyone,
even Ishbalans.
Mom said it was awful
that they got killed.
You say they were killed by a State Alchemist?
They say he was an alchemist who used flame.
He got a commendation for it.
Mom cried over it, huh?
M-Miss!
The wounds didn't have
any burns around them?
No. What's more,
if they had been bullet wounds,
the entry wounds should be larger than the exit wounds, but they aren't.
Brother, these are...
There's a lieutenant colonel in Central named Archer, right?
He's going after these guys that are called homunculi.
Homunculi?
One of them is a monster that can quickly extend her fingers, like thin spears,
and then quickly retract them back to normal.
The thickness is about right.
Lt. Col. Archer or Major Armstrong would believe this.
It wasn't an Ishbalan.
I can't very well ignore the word of
an esteemed State Alchemist, huh?
Hey, come on!
Yow-ow-ow!
Winry?
Rick, Leo, I managed to get them to overlook anything you might have done.
What's more, the people who are
being held here will not be punished.
They are going to be
sent to the camp, though.
If you guys want, you can go live in Resembool.
No, we'll go to the camp.
I see.
Where are you two going?
We're going to go after Scar.
If we don't, something terrible is going to happen.
Will you kill him?
Why would I?
Because he's an outcast!
He's defiled! That's why!
We want to stop him.
After all, we're alchemists,
just like he is.
No, we're human.
We won't kill anyone, and we don't want to let him kill anyone.
You're lying!
You hate Ishbalans!
Does this scare you?
Not even a little!
Well... I'm a little bit
afraid of your red eyes.
The first time I met Scar, he was
the first Ishbalan I had ever seen,
so I was more afraid of him.
Still,
there are times when
our feelings are wrong.
What your mother and father told you isn't necessarily completely true.
That's why...
we all have to find our own answers for ourselves.
One step at a time.
Winry, listen...
That being the case—
I'm going to Central.
Hawkeye-san, could you take me with you?
It's been so long, and I'd like to see Hughes-san and Elicia-chan.
Sure.
Winry, has something happened?
Well then, first up is Ishbal.
I sure hope Scar-san hasn't
made his Philosopher's Stone.
Yeah.
It sounds so strange,
us hoping for such a thing.
What does this switch do?
Lieutenant...
Riza is fine.
Riza-san, have you ever shot anyone?
Yes, I have. Many times.
Did you know any doctors by the name of Rockbell?
Yes.
I'm not sure what you know,
but there are times when a soldier has
no choice but to take another person's life.
Even when they're following orders that are irrational.
Maybe that's why I don't like soldiers very much.
But you're in the military.
That's because there is
someone I need to protect.
That is the one thing that
nobody has forced me to do.
It's something I decided myself.
I pull this trigger of my own will,
for the sake of the one I need to protect.
Until the day when
that person achieves his goal,
I will not hesitate
to pull this trigger.
What if that person
was not worth protecting?
That is something else
for me to decide.
This boy is Wrath.
He is the seventh.
Wrath?
Nice to meet you, Wrath.
I want you to go after the
Fullmetal brothers once again.
Didn't you tell us that there was little hope of making them create a Philosopher's Stone?
The two of them
are heading for Ishbal.
I see.
If those boys learn the facts about what happened there,
they will never think again about making a Philosopher's Stone.
That will make it harder for us to move from here on as well.
Then can I eat them?
Maybe. Depending on the circumstances, it might be quicker to dispose of them.
I'm sorry. I didn't know anything about this.
"I'm going to push him all the way to the top."
That's what he
always used to say.
He was sure he was going to make Mustang-san the Führer.
This can't be...
I suppose he did
help out to that end.
This can't be...
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 37: "The Flame Alchemist,
The Fighting Lieutenant,
The Mystery of Warehouse 13"